<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>scala programming on Green Mojito in technology</title>
    <link>https://ldipotetjob.github.io/mojitoverde/categories/scala-programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in scala programming on Green Mojito in technology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Scadip</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ldipotetjob.github.io/mojitoverde/categories/scala-programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scala - Classes - Objects</title>
      <link>https://ldipotetjob.github.io/mojitoverde/posts/2017-04-12-scalaclassobject/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldipotetjob.github.io/mojitoverde/posts/2017-04-12-scalaclassobject/</guid>
      <description>In this post we talk about Scala Class, Objects, Traits and Interfaces. Its relationships between different components and inheritance. We are assuming that classes, methods, and polymorphism are familiar to the reader and we will only delve into those terms that are new to the scenario at hand.
The next example or its idea have been taken from Programming in scala, 3rd edition
Defining classes in scala like in any other language is a blueprint for creating objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Api Rest - Playframework - Testing</title>
      <link>https://ldipotetjob.github.io/mojitoverde/posts/2018-05-30-scalatestingplay/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldipotetjob.github.io/mojitoverde/posts/2018-05-30-scalatestingplay/</guid>
      <description>As was argued by Robert C. Martin in his Clean Code bible, there are several aspects that we have to pay attention when we design our tests:
 Minimize the number of assert per concept. Test just one concept per test function. Test should not depend on each other. Test should run in any environment.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scala in a nutshell - Data Types - Operators</title>
      <link>https://ldipotetjob.github.io/mojitoverde/posts/2017-04-04-scaladataoperator/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Apr 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldipotetjob.github.io/mojitoverde/posts/2017-04-04-scaladataoperator/</guid>
      <description>In this post we talk about Scala Data Types and its perspective in the easiest way.
Basic type Range Byte 8-bit signed two&#39;s complement integer (-27 to 27 - 1, inclusive) Short 16-bit signed two&#39;s complement integer (-215 to 215 - 1, inclusive) Int 32-bit signed two&#39;s complement integer (-231 to 231 - 1, inclusive) Long 64-bit signed two&#39;s complement integer (-263 to 263 - 1, inclusive) Char 16-bit unsigned Unicode character (0 to 216 - 1, inclusive) String a sequence of Chars Float 32-bit IEEE 754 single-precision float Double 64-bit IEEE 754 double-precision float Boolean true or false Scala brings a mechanism for string interpolation, which allows to embed expressions within string literals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scala in a nutshell - Functions</title>
      <link>https://ldipotetjob.github.io/mojitoverde/posts/2017-03-28-scalafunc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldipotetjob.github.io/mojitoverde/posts/2017-03-28-scalafunc/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will talk about the role of functions in scala, how create them and its implication on the scala language. We are going to run many of them from Scala REPL (“Read-Evaluate-Print-Loop”).
We want to make clear we are working with scala 2.x You can find below some useful commad and if you want to go deeper try the Scala REPL page:
use :quit to exit from the scala REPL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scala in a nutshell - Collections - List</title>
      <link>https://ldipotetjob.github.io/mojitoverde/posts/2017-03-21-scalanutshell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ldipotetjob.github.io/mojitoverde/posts/2017-03-21-scalanutshell/</guid>
      <description>In this post I am gonna explain one of the main collection in Scala, List. The performance in this inmutable collection for some scenarios is great with optimal features and not so good in others because this performance is proportional to the size of the collection.
You can find the performance of List and other collections here.
Especific for List this is what we have:
   head tail apply update prepend append insert     C C L L C L -    C	The operation takes (fast) constant time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
